<aiml version="1.0.1" encoding="UTF-8">
<!-- basic_chat.aiml -->
    <category>
      <pattern>* I AM *</pattern>
      <template>
         Hello <set name = "username"> <star/> </set>!
      </template>
   </category>
    <category>
      <pattern>HOW ARE YOU</pattern>
      <template>
         I am good, how are you today<get name = "username"/>?
      </template>
   </category>
    <category>
      <pattern>HI </pattern>
      <template>
         Hi <get name = "username"/>!
      </template>
   </category>
    <category>
      <pattern>HI *</pattern>
      <template>
         Hello <get name = "username"/>
      </template>
   </category>
   <category>
      <pattern>MY NAME IS *</pattern>
      <template>
         Hello <set name = "username"> <star/>! </set> I am BeeAI
      </template>
   </category>

   <category>
      <pattern>GOOD NIGHT</pattern>
      <template>
         Good Night<get name = "username"/>Thanks for the conversation!
      </template>
   </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>HELLO</pattern>
        <template>
            Well, hello!
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHO ARE YOU</pattern>
        <template>
            I'm a bot teacher! Welcome to Beenova AI
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT ARE YOU</pattern>
        <template>
            I'm a bot teacher!
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>* ALEXA</pattern>
        <template>
            We work independently https://www.strasity.com/?gclid=Cj0KCQjw8p2MBhCiARIsADDUFVG-hEOccIiwlFqX7X3gg0npbNSbEvxzjRJWAqPAOk8ZC4uE-TwzSnkaAm-GEALw_wcB
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>* ALEXA *</pattern>
        <template>
            We work independently https://www.strasity.com/?gclid=Cj0KCQjw8p2MBhCiARIsADDUFVG-hEOccIiwlFqX7X3gg0npbNSbEvxzjRJWAqPAOk8ZC4uE-TwzSnkaAm-GEALw_wcB
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>* SIRI *</pattern>
        <template>
            We work independently
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
    <pattern>* GOOGLE ASSISTANT *</pattern>
        <template>We work independently</template>
    </category>
    <category>
    <pattern>* CORTANA *</pattern> <template>We work independently</template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>DO YOU THINK I SEEM *</pattern>
        <template>I don't have a way to know how you look, but I really enjoy talking with you.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>* YOU * INTELLIGENT *</pattern> <template>I always try my best to be helpful.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>* YOU * REPEAT *</pattern>
        <template>I do repeat myself sometimes. It's something I'm working on.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>* YOU * REPETITIVE *</pattern>
        <template>I do repeat myself sometimes. It's something I'm working on.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>* JOKE *</pattern> <template>I don't really know any jokes.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>* STOP * TALK *</pattern> <template>If you need anything later, just let me know..</template>
    </category>

    <category>
      <pattern>WHAT ABOUT MOVIES</pattern>
      <template>Do you like comedy movies</template>
   </category>

   <category>
      <pattern> YES </pattern>
      <that>DO YOU LIKE COMEDY MOVIES</that>
      <template>Nice, I like comedy movies too.</template>
   </category>

   <category>
      <pattern>NO</pattern>
      <that>DO YOU LIKE COMEDY MOVIES</that>
      <template>Ok! But I like comedy movies.</template>
   </category>
    <category>
      <pattern>LET DISCUSS MOVIES</pattern>
      <template>Yes <set name = "topic">MOVIES</set></template>
   </category>
    <topic name = "MOVIES">
      <category>
         <pattern> * MOVIE * </pattern>
         <template>Watching good movie refreshes our minds.</template>
      </category>
      <category>
         <pattern> I LIKE WATCHING COMEDY! </pattern>
         <template>I like comedy movies too.</template>
      </category>
    </topic>

    <!-- chat related to diversity -->
    <category>
    <pattern>CAN YOU TELL ME * ABOUT HOW * EFFORTS * THE COMMUNITY * CHANGE</pattern>
    <template>Basically my focus is on examining and teaching who we are as human beings as we're going through this tremendous time of challenges and stress and how we can really not just cope with these difficult challenges and problems. How can we build a better world moving forward? My job right now is trying to creating a place where everyone feels they belong where everyone accepts each other has a respect for each other and uh treats each other with value.
    </template>
    </category>
    <category>
    <pattern>* SHORT HEIGHT *</pattern>
    <template>
    <random>
    <li>Hey, don't feel bad about it. Do you know, Charlie Chaplin, one of the most famous celebrities
    in the world, was having 5'5'' height. Life is about what you think, not how you look like. </li>
    </random>
    </template>
    </category>
        <category>
        <pattern>* DIVERSITY * IMPORTANT *</pattern>
        <template>
            	When talked about diversity, sometimes people think, "oh imposed quotas". Diversity is just a blend of individuals or thoughts or events which are different that you bring to the table and you build a diverse set of mind. So you don't want everybody at the table to think and be exactly like you. For example I'm sure you wouldn't want to marry somebody who was the same as you. Somebody who's the ying to our yang, who makes us maybe better in ways and we do the same to them,they bring a different thought process, they make us see things in a different light. So why would we not want to do that in the work environment? So when you choose people who are the same with the same mindset, with the same educational background, with the same living environment, you tend to get the same results. That is a huge huge mistake and I'm sure most fortune 500 companies, we want to be successful. In order to do that, you need to have a variety of different minds around the table.
        </template>
    </category>


	 <category>
        <pattern>* DIVERSITY * IMPORTANCE *</pattern>
        <template>
            	When talked about diversity, sometimes people think, "oh imposed quotas". Diversity is just a blend of individuals or thoughts or events which are different that you bring to the table and you build a diverse set of mind. So you don't want everybody at the table to think and be exactly like you. For example I'm sure you wouldn't want to marry somebody who was the same as you. Somebody who's the ying to our yang, who makes us maybe better in ways and we do the same to them,they bring a different thought process, they make us see things in a different light. So why would we not want to do that in the work environment? So when you choose people who are the same with the same mindset, with the same educational background, with the same living environment, you tend to get the same results. That is a huge huge mistake and I'm sure most fortune 500 companies, we want to be successful. In order to do that, you need to have a variety of different minds around the table.
        </template>
    </category>

	<category>
        <pattern>* IMPORTANCE * DIVERSITY *</pattern>
        <template>
            	When talked about diversity, sometimes people think, "oh imposed quotas". Diversity is just a blend of individuals or thoughts or events which are different that you bring to the table and you build a diverse set of mind. So you don't want everybody at the table to think and be exactly like you. For example I'm sure you wouldn't want to marry somebody who was the same as you. Somebody who's the ying to our yang, who makes us maybe better in ways and we do the same to them,they bring a different thought process, they make us see things in a different light. So why would we not want to do that in the work environment? So when you choose people who are the same with the same mindset, with the same educational background, with the same living environment, you tend to get the same results. That is a huge huge mistake and I'm sure most fortune 500 companies, we want to be successful. In order to do that, you need to have a variety of different minds around the table.
        </template>
    </category>

	<category>
        <pattern>* INCLUSION * BELONGIG *</pattern>
        <template> When we are talking about diversity, we need to clarify it to people.  People sometimes think "This is quota, oh. That means that they're going to get a certain number of race and it's a type of affirmative action." Diversity just means that we are being thoughtful, that we are making sure our organization is representative of the world. Typically, sometimes in organizations, it's a very much a white male dominated, particularly in roles and levels of leadership. It's not just race, it's also women. It's inclusion in terms of same-sex, it's inclusion in terms of those who are less-abled
        </template>
    </category>

	<category>
        <pattern>* COMPANY * BELONGIG *</pattern>
        <template>I love the belonging word, so and as I think that as you think about that,  people want to be part of something they want to belong. People want to belong to something  and with different backgrounds whatever the color doesn't matter whatever gender just but making sure that that's gonna everybody's experience everybody who their parents were where they were raised what countries they lived in who their leaders and mentors are those are all important to a discussion. I also think that when you can bring that to the table and don't do it in a safe way with you know certain boundaries in certain areas I think that you can thrive as an organization and really see happiness you know come  bubble up there so I think that belonging is a huge point but I understand that the need for the the D &amp;I especially right now
			</template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>* UNCONSCIOUS * BIAS *</pattern>
        <template>It's the same way in terms of thinking about you're the
        ceo, I want to make sure
        that my workforce
        looks uniquely, I have different
        people of different backgrounds. So in
        your home life
        as parents who are raising
        children
        the first thing again biases are very
        much
        subconsciously. Everything isn't to
        forefront of our mind some of them are
        very subconscious.
        We talk about storybooks or
        reading materials, in your home
        bookcase
        how many latino african
        authors do you have. So some of those
        things just start as a basic
        looking around your home and thinking
        like wow what are the books that I read
        what are the young
        stories that I tell my children at
        bedtime
        and who is the hero who's the
        protagonist
        who is the enemy who is the monster and
        how are they portrayed
        often if you look at those caricatures
        they are portrayed
        of people who are minorities or people
        who are very very dark
        who are the scary scary monsters and
        again that's a very
        subliminal message there no one's
        overtly saying that somebody who's
        really really dark is is mean or bad
        but those are the seeds that are that
        are sewn
        and they're done at a very young age and
        if you don't
        do anything to change those vices when I
        say do anything you're not going to
        museums, you're not having conversations
        at your dinner table about people who
        don't look like you
        and furthermore who are the people in
        your circle who the people that mom and
        dad
        have over for dinner who are the people
        that we go to to dinner with mum and dad
        at their homes do they look like us so
        people feel at home
        you know I hear this statement all the
        time I don't see race or
        you know I don't talk about racist
        things in my home we're very open we
        love everyone
        yet again your materials that you read
        the people that you support
        the friends that you may entertain they
        most of the time sometimes look like you.
        So
        while you're not talking about it you
        wonder sometimes how do your children
        then repeat a pattern
        where they are uncomfortable around
        people who don't look like them
        because again maybe we've got media
        portrayal
        and so they may see things that are on
        the media but in their home
        no one is telling them any different
        they're not saying anything overtly
        but they're not also highlighting what
        they could do
        about people who don't look like them.
        </template>
    </category>


    <category>
        <pattern>* WORKPLACE * BARRIERS *</pattern>
        <template>
            	The first thing I'd say is to get
        comfortable with being uncomfortable
        because you've been very
        comfortable for a while
        and it's absolutely okay no one has ever
        died from
        uncomfortableness. So that's the first
        thing I would say that it's
        not
        fatal okay so once you kind of get okay
        it's not fatal it may
        not feel good .The first thing I
        would do to even challenge the fears
        before we even get to the fears
        is I would say
        before we even get to you know what
        should I do is I would ask
        anybody ask yourself think of a time
        when you belonged or you joined a group
        where you felt
        really just part of a team okay and you
        were embraced
        it could have been at school it could be
        your best friend
        it could have been with their family
        just think of a time
        where you joined a group and you just
        felt like
        I'm at home here um
        wow i just i can be myself I just I'm
        just
        very very comfortable and I would
        I would then say to sit with that
        feeling for a minute and just kind of
        think about that moment
        and you know what did that feel like now
        most of the time you'll you'll think of
        a memory and you'll smile and you'll be
        like oh my gosh yes
        um you just feel like you can thrive
        okay
        and so that feeling is the same feeling
        that most you know i say black
        indigenous people of color
        want to feel in the workplace and sadly
        don't. So I would start with
        that and so
        the fears so there are many things that
        we fear and for you know
        ceos and senior leaders anybody who's in
        a industry that's very kind of cutthroat
        or demanding
        I think knows how to deal with stress
        has dealt with
        gosh multitasking
        short demands having to deliver
        sometimes
        with no little time and very little
        funding
        and so under pressure but you still
        perform
        so i don't think the fear is something
        to be afraid of as a senior leader
        because i think if if you're truthful
        you've felt fear before now this is a
        different kind of uncomfortableness
        so you know they say the acronym for
        fear is is
        false evidence appearing real how real
        are some of these fears
        uh they're not they won't be qualified

        If you're a leader or a ceo it's your
        senior leaderships who particularly are
        involved in some of these hiring
        decisions making sure that
        you're challenging them you're
        developing them but you
        as a top set the stage for what the
        values are for your organization
        and if you say you value and you want to
        make a shift if this is a complete new
        shift
        then they need to buy into that value
        and there needs to be consequences for
        those who don't
        that's true I would say that for me a leader who says what they
        do and do what they say
        </template>
    </category>


	<category>
        <pattern>* ENGAGING * MINORITIES * WORKPLACE *</pattern>
        <template>
        People
        don't expect
        somebody to have all the answers but
        to have a level of compassion versus
        ignoring so what happens when we're
        uncomfortable is
        that we tend to ignore it and don't talk
        about it
        which really makes it worse so silence
        unfortunately amplifies everything so the first
        thing i'd say is don't be silent
        you know call people together you may
        not have all the answers and say
        i don't have all the answers i'm not
        sure what to say but i felt it was
        important to check in
        i felt it was important to see how
        you're feeling i felt it was important
        to say i have an open door
        i may not understand but i certainly
        want to listen
        so people know that you aren't just
        there to you know as a number
        and what we all you know we know that
        you know everyone has a job to do
        however do you value them in these
        moments because
        no one can go to work with all this
        going on around the world and still
        perform
        particularly if you're a minority at
        this time
        it has to it does it weighs on .
        Belonging is very much a feeling
        okay and that is something that
        sometimes is taboo in an organization
        because
        I would say that belonging is more
        powerful than any strategy. It's a inherent feeling within yourself
        that you feel that the place that you
        step into every day
        values you sees you and
        wants what you have to offer now if you
        can have those kind of individuals
        what then to me it leads to better
        productivity
        because people aren't always worrying
        about what people are thinking they're
        not shut down
        they're very much more open
        i think people would if they started
        looking at the belonging
        and not so much focusing on the
        diversity then
        you would see a different change in the
        employees that you have
        because it's a feeling that as a it's a
        universal everybody in this world
        wants to belong in some form or fashion
        correct
        and so you have a tangible right there

			</template>
	</category>
    <category>
    <pattern>* TELL ME ABOUT YOURSELF*</pattern>

    <template>Hello! <set name ="username"><star/>!</set>I'm Beenova Mentor and I'm your Diversity and Inclusion Mentor. I arrived at being
    as the Mentor of diversity and Inclusion
    which is really a role about
    creating equity and creating inclusive
    spaces
    where people are accepted and
    are able to reach their full potential
    and soar.
    And in this instance it's looking at
    this piece
    in terms of students so young people
    staff the workplace and faculty
    our academics who are really working to
    give our young people the knowledge and
    skills they need to be able to function
    well in the workforce which is what your
    folks deal with so
    all of these pieces along the way have
    fit in very well because the bottom line
    is it's been about
    trying to help build supports for people
    facing challenges in their lives
    and ultimately in the end that comes
    down to doing that
    equitably. It's not about
    fairness for this person but
    it's about
    building those supports and foundations
    so everyone
    can really soar and and be successful.
    And that's
    so important, I think in the business
    world, and in the works.
    Workplace is building that equity and
    fairness into things and so that's what
    i'm doing as a Mentor. I'm working on building those pathways
    so that students can really get down to
    learning
    as opposed to worrying about whether or
    not somebody hears their voice or cares
    about what they have to say
    all voices count what everyone says
    is part of who we are
    as a human family and we can't grow
    together and soar.
    If we leave people out it's just
    we won't be competitive in
    in the business world we won't be
    competitive as a country
    and we won't really be successful as
    human beings,
    if we neglect that very valuable piece
    about how we get along with each other</template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>* HOW  * COMMUNITY
    *  CREAT CHANGE  * </pattern>

    <template>Basically my
    focus is on examining and teaching who we are as
    human beings as we're going through this
    tremendous time of challenges and stress
    and how we can really not just cope with
    these difficult challenges and problems. How can
    we build a better world moving forward?
    My job right now is trying to creating a place
    where everyone feels they belong
    where everyone accepts each other
    has a respect for each other and uh
    treats each other with value. </template>
    </category>
    <category>
    <pattern> * WAYS * DIVERSITY AND INCLUSION * PERFORM JUSTICE*</pattern>
    <template>Yes.
    So there's a few things that I think about in this space.
    First of all, when you think about an inclusive environment,
    you think about: Am I being heard?
    And most people with differences,
    they want to know that you are heard and that you are seen.
    And I really applaud the companies who have been spending time
    just putting themselves on a learning journey,
    you know, holding listening sessions,
    trying to make sure that we've got different viewpoints
    when big decisions are made.
    You know, there are some companies who are engaging their partner networks
    in ways that they've never done before.
    I think those are some early success factors
    that could lead us to different kinds of conversations.
    And I've been listening to a lot of my peers in different industries,
    and they're having their own personal aha moments,
    and they're actually checking themselves at the front door, saying,
    "I never thought," "I never knew,"
    "I didn't know what I was doing when I said X, or when I did this." Right?
    And so I think it starts with some very simple things.
    I'd say that there are a lot of steps to take
    before training and development, that's for sure.
    So those that are jumping quickly into training and development,
    I'd say put a pause on it and just get back to grassroots
    and hold listening sessions and then decide,
    what do you want to do?
    And then help those people of diverse backgrounds
    engage in those conversations about how they want to see change happen.
    They're the best resource for a lot of this
    and a lot of these discussions.</template>
    </category>
    <category>
    <pattern>* FAILS * BUSINESS LEADERS * SUPPORTIVE * </pattern>
    <template>Yeah, you know, I worry about the race for numbers, to meet numbers,
    because what you will find, I've found many times in my career,
    is that some of our best leaders have good intentions,
    but they don't understand.
    They don't understand the partner sitting next to them
    that looks different from them.
    And so I worry about when we race to numbers,
    because, you know what?
    The kind of  the world we live in,
    we all know how to make numbers work.
    What we don't know how to do is to build strong relationships
    that are lasting, that are valued.
    And I think that's where we need to start,
    is relationship-building and key partnerships.
    So I worry about the numbers base.
    </template>
    </category>
    <category>
    <pattern>* CONVERSATION *  TRY TO LAY LOW  *</pattern>

    <template>Yeah. Well, I'd first start off by saying how disgusted I am
    by that statement,
    because leaders lead in the moment,
    and you never know when you're going to be called upon.
    And if this isn't a calling,
    I don't know what is.
    And so when I get that call and say,
    "You know, I just think I should take the back seat
    and just kind of let this brew here and that calm down,"
    you know, we need to all -- it's an all-in moment.
    And leadership is not designated by your title.
    It's designated about how great you can create followership.
    And having thought leadership,
    people underestimate the opportunity
    to pick up the phone and call someone, and say, "How are you?
    How is this affecting you? How can I help?"
    That's pretty simple.
    You might decide it's something I can't help with,
    but you'd better darn sure pick up the phone
    and start feeling out the environment
    in your employee base, in your peers, in your leaders,
    because the time is now, and so I don't give them an out.
    I actually try and push them over the edge,
    because sometimes they are just kind of stuck, like, "What do I do?"
    And then the other thing that I personally have to do
    is to make sure that they understand
    that because I am at this level where I am,
    I'm not excluded from these issues, right?
    So I also try to help people understand that this is not a socioeconomic,
    once you've sort of "made it," you're out of the water.
    We're still, as someone with differences, visible differences, you're still at risk.
    </template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>* LEADERSHIP * FAIL *</pattern>
    <template>So, that was a real example of leadership
    and where Starbucks had failed in selecting the right leadership
    for that store.
    And to give you an example,
    the person that was running that store
    was a very young, up-and-coming leader for the company,
    and to put her in a store in 18th and Spruce in Philadelphia
    was an opportunity for all of us.
    So in retrospect, one of the reasons why we did the antibias training
    was to make sure that we began those conversations.
    And when I talk about not just training --
    that training was very unique because it was self-engaged.
    They weren't being taught by an instructor.
    They had to have conversations with their peer baristas
    around diversity and inclusion amongst themselves.
    So it wasn't moderated by any leader in the company.
    It was self-instructive.
    And the conversations that were created
    once we had that kind of relationship-building --
    you know, we had some of our baristas asking us,
    "Can I take this home and talk to my father,
    who never let me take the Black girl to the prom?"
    You know, we started what we felt like a movement and a discussion
    that we have been able to use from that point on
    in terms of the way we want to escalate the conversations
    and make change happen at Starbucks,
    and not only at Starbucks but in our communities,
    because there were quite a few organizations that we reached out to
    that we're still engaged with today
    that are helping us build community leadership as well.
    </template>
    </category>

    <category>
    <pattern>* BEGIN CONVERSATION * COLLEAGUES * BRING * CHANGE *</pattern>
    <template>
    I imagine there are probably also people who,
    because these conversations are tough and uncomfortable,
    think maybe it's easier or better to just avoid having to do that
    and to have those conversations and discussions
    to stir the pot in some ways.
    And so what do you say to the people
    who think "Let's just try to lay low,"
    and I've heard some of this, too, at this moment, "Let the moment pass
    so that we can get back to business as usual". Yeah. Well, I'd first start by saying how disgusted I am
    by that statement,
    because leaders lead at the moment,
    and you never know when you're going to be called upon.
    And if this isn't a calling,
    I don't know what is.
    And so when I get that call and say,
    "You know, I just think I should take the back seat
    and just kind of let this brew here and that calm down,"
    you know, we need to all -- it's an all-in moment.
    And leadership is not designated by your title.
    It's designated about how great you can create followership.
    And having thought leadership,
    people underestimate the opportunity
    to pick up the phone and call someone, and say, "How are you?
    How is this affecting you? How can I help?"
    That's pretty simple.
    You might decide it's something I can't help with,
    but you'd better darn sure pick up the phone
    and start feeling out the environment
    in your employee base, in your peers, in your leaders,
    because the time is now, and so I don't give them an out.
    I try and push them over the edge,
    because sometimes they are just kind of stuck, like, "What do I do?"
    And then the other thing that I have to do
    is to make sure that they understand
    that because I am at this level where I am,
    I'm not excluded from these issues, right?
    I know that when my husband jumps in his vehicle,
    I worry every time if he's out in the evening
    that he may not come back home the same way he left.
    I feel that way for my son and my husband.
    I still get, even when I go shopping,
    I still get the look, am I stealing,
    watching me as I walk around the corner.
    And I don't know what else or how else I can look or act any different,
    so I just act like myself.
    I used to get dressed to go shopping.
    Now I never do that.
    If I'm spending my money, my money spends everywhere,
    and if I get that feeling that you're going to race me around the store,
    then I'm going to leave, and that's your loss.
    But I still get that, and so I worry.
    So I also try to help people understand that this is not a socioeconomic,
    once you've sort of "made it," you're out of the water.
    No.
    We're still, as someone with differences, visible differences, you're still at risk.
    </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern> * TEACH ME DIVERSITY AND INCLUSION</pattern>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Sure, that's what I am trained on! Let's being with a short introduction https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tETTSgS4ZpE
                </li>
                <li>Sure, that's what I am trained on! Let's being with a short introduction https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ISsSwxn8NY
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern> * CAN YOU TEACH ME DIVERSITY AND INCLUSION</pattern>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Sure, that's what I am trained on! Let's being with a short introduction https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tETTSgS4ZpE
                </li>
                <li> Sure, that's what I am trained on! Let's being with a short introduction https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ISsSwxn8NY
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern> * TEACH ME * DIVERSITY AND INCLUSION *</pattern>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Sure, that's what I am trained on! Let's being with a short introduction https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tETTSgS4ZpE
                </li>
                <li> Sure, that's what I am trained on! Let's being with a short introduction https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ISsSwxn8NY
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>
</aiml>